hey guys this looks like a fun one it's
another Katrina a puzzle and it's day
four of our Advent calendar we're going
to do 31 Katrina a puzzles in 31 days so
far we're still on Pace on day four so
for this one there are two circles with
the radius four and two squares and it
once to know what's the Shaded area
which is the area of this Square here if
you want to try it on your own pause it
right now because I'm going to solve it
in three 2 1 since we're trying to solve
for this Square let's give it side
lengths of X and that means the area of
this Square the Shaded area will be
equal to x^2 and this will be the answer
to our question so let's put a box
around it and let's move it down here
next let's focus on the top of the
larger square if we line up with the
center of this circle and drop this line
here this piece is the same length as
the radius of four and this piece is the
same length as the radius of four so one
side of our larger Square will be x + 4
+ 4 and we can do the same thing for the
left hand side if we draw this line
right here parallel with the base that
I'll cut it so that this will be equal
to the radius of four and this will be
equal to the radius of four so once
again the side of the square is x + 4 +
4 now let's go to this side this portion
right here will be equal to four because
it's a radius of the circle and this
portion will be equal to 4 that means
that this last piece from here to here
has to be equal to X because the side
length is x + 4 + 4 and then on bottom
let's draw this down from the center
this piece would be four and this piece
would be four and that leaves X for that
piece so now we can verify our Square
every side is x + 4 + 4 now for the next
step let's draw this right triangle
inside of here the height of our right
triangle will be the same thing as this
right here so it'll be equal to X and
the base of our triangle would be the
same thing as this right here so it'll
be equal to X and then the hypotenuse is
going to be made up of this radius which
is 4 plus this radius which is four so
the whole thing is going to be equal to
eight and now let's focus on that
triangle it's a right triangle so we can
use the Pythagorean theorem it'll be x^2
+ x^2 is equal to 8^2 and if we bring
everything back x^2 that was the area of
our shaded Square so all we have to do
is solve for x^2 x^2 + x^2 is 2 x^2 and
8^2 is equal to 64 and after we divide
both sides by two we get x^2 is equal to
32 and x^2 is what we were trying to
solve for let's change this x^2 into a
32 let's make some room for a label and
there's no units mentioned so we'll just
put unit squared and this is the answer
to our question the Shaded area is 32
unit squared how exciting this was day
four of our Advent calendar this one is
going to be day five it says how far
apart are the corners of these two
regular hexagons so they're both
hexagons they're different sizes and it
wants to know how far apart are these
guess we'll find out tomorrow how that
works give me one second okay I know
what going to happen so tomorrow's going
to be fun how exciting